that lets you focus to some of the
earnings and focusing on Karnataka bank
now because this time around the company
has reported a good set with a jump of
almost 171 onto their profits on a yui
basis let's try to find out what is the
Outlook going ahead when it comes to the
number growth and to talk more on that
we have shekhar Rao who is the executive
director and interim MD and CEO of
Karnataka bank I have very good morning
Shaker thank you so much for joining us
today on ET now firstly congratulations
on a good set of numbers but looking at
your internals this time if we see then
the banks loan growth was quite lower
than when we compare that with the
larger sector or or some of your larger
pairs so what's holding the loan growth
back for you
firstly thank you for your compliments
uh yeah we have indeed declared uh
fairly encouraging results uh in fact it
is ahead of our peers also on your
specific question on the loan growth if
you see our Q3 results uh we were
tracking along tracking along at a 12
growth in our asset book in Q4 we face
this difficult decision of whether to
continue this momentum or retire some
low yielding
advances which I write rates below the G
secrets uh so since our financials were
looking healthy uh we took the decision
to buy the bullet and we retired some of
this uh high low yielding advances and
that's where our advances growth look a
little limited this also given us an
opportunity to conserve some liquidity
for the retail plans that we have
yeah
right uh good morning uh Mr Rao this is
Cheryl also joining in the conversation
uh yes just like us would like to Echo
the similar sentiment congratulations
good set of numbers if you look at
Karnataka Bank over the last one year on
all parameters uh there's only a marked
improvement that the bank has registered
uh I want to ask specifically on your
Nims number uh if you look at the
quarter gone by your Nims stood at
around 3.87 which is a marked recovery
when you see on a quadrant quarter basis
uh where do you see limbs headed in the
new Financial year there's fy24 do you
expect to surpass these level or
maintain these levels
we would also see some increase in cost
of deposit uh we see this seems to be
range bound between 3.5 3.70
okay Mr Rao if we look at your asset
quality now so for the whole of the
banking space we have seen that
improving but sequentially if we say
then your NPA numbers uh have seen a
rise as well as your gnpa numbers on a
YY basis uh that have seen a growth over
there so what is keeping your NPA
numbers at an elevated level and going
ahead any guidance on both of these
numbers
uh yes uh again uh in Q4 uh the top line
numbers gave us this opportunity to do
some accelerated provisioning so we
identified some stressed accounts uh and
we move them so there we had the
opportunity of qualifying them as glpl
and to an accelerated provisioning as
well that's why you would see a higher
professional provisioning levels in Q4
uh this is a one-time exercise and going
forward you will see uh this coming down
significantly uh we basically relied on
the health of the balance sheet to do
this exercise
all right uh let's talk about your Ro is
then where should one actually see Ros
for Karnataka Bank in the new uh year
that's F5 2004 and what are the larger
goals of the banks in terms of growth
and roas for the next three years
we have a new leadership that is at uh
at Karnataka Bank
yeah uh uh firstly on the new leadership
uh in fact uh back has identified uh the
new managing director
um a carrier Banker
three Krishna will be will be joining us
uh he comes from a stellar linkage uh
having worked with uh
Geo payments Bank having run his own
firm and HDFC and he's been part of the
HDFC founding team as well he comes in
with impeccable credentials the same
line with the bank stated polls of
transforming and inducting laterals of
high quality so so we welcome into the
bank he'll formally join the bank on on
the 9th of June uh coming to your Roa uh
question I would have said against at
this moment but we will see Roa uh to be
around current levels or marginally
higher than what it is
cost the
uh the third point of uh what will be
the band Spoon uh going forward so this
this uh coincidentally is our secondary
year we are in our 100th year of
existence so we have planned uh a fair
bit of action during the upcoming year
but my strategic level uh the big change
is our retail focus in fact as we speak
we have in fact realigned our
organization structure to focus on
retail we now have a more linear retail
focused or structure with verticals for
Branch Banking retail advances uh so on
and so forth we also have a product team
which will support the uh the sales team
these uh We've rolled out uh product
simplification in Road loans our home
loan also has the Homegrown product has
also seen an upgrade we see our headline
interested in homegrown at 8.75 which is
fairly competitive
we are increasing our asset processing
hubs moving from three to five to eight
during the year this will also improve
our tag this will give us a special uh I
mean this will give us increased ability
to scale up retail and msnly as well uh
while we are doing this we are really
doing the entire underwriting process
and simplifying how we underwrite
retailers
costs are trending uh down currently so
should one expect to see a spike in your
cost to income in FY 24 and where are
you investing currently
ah so uh yes the costs are trading now
currently but we will see some little it
will see a marginal increase from
current levels because we will see a
increased activity in employee
provisions and also addition of head
count particularly in the technology
product and digital space most of our
investments could be the attack on
digital space we are consolidating all
our Tech and digital into a factory in
Bangalore which will give us the the
entire and at this office will be I came
to a fintech and less similar to a bank
so our investments will be in this space
we also are making some small
infrastructure
Investments aligned to our centinary
year so we have a commemorative
Centenary building coming up but large
Investments would be in hiring for
specialist resources particularly
product technology digital and for in
fact our Tech budget for the upcoming
year is either 80 increase this will be
our focusing is
and lastly let me just ask you one last
question uh Mr Rao what are the larger
risks that you foresee in FY 24 we did
our talk about where do you see your
names your grocer and P as well the
larger risk that you foresee in fy24 and
also where do you see credit cross and
provisioning trending from your own I
know you've alluded to this particular
uh question even or other topic in your
previous answer
in fact uh as as a sector uh I would say
the uncertainty associated with the
macro economic scenario
um the rate increase Etc we've almost
seen the worst behind us now we have
seen greater predictability coming going
up ahead uh but there will be so one
minor risk would be on on the
compression of nibs which we wish to
plan to address via change in product
picks our as we see now our
most important Focus area would be the
need to grow and Retail and raw market
share and this is where we will focus
our Collective Energies
okay Mr Rao we'll let you go on that
thank you so much for joining us today
on E3 now and helping with the growth
outlook for the Karnataka Bank